# Thobio Joseph

Self-taught iOS Developer with 6.2 years of experience. Started career in iOS development as a freelancer. Later joined Zerone Consulting Pvt Ltd in Cochin, Kerala as a Senior Software Engineer. Currently working at WNPL in NSW, Australia. Has a graduation degree in Computer Application from Marian College.

Nalukody Po. Changanacherry Kerala, India

+919048128845

jthobio2@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/ thobio-joseph-529a29133/

### **EXPERIENCE**

**WNPL**, Australia(Remote) — Senior iOS Developer

January 2021 - PRESENT

**ZERONE CONSULTING**, Cochin — Senior iOS Developer

October 2017 - January 2021

FOURART DESIGNS PVT. LTD., Cochin, — iOS Developer

May 2016 - September 2017

### **EDUCATION**

**Marian College,** Kuttikkanam — BCA (BACHELOR OF COMPUTER APPLICATIONS)

June 2010 - July 2013

### **PROJECTS**

# **ALDI Efficiency**

Aldi is the common brand of two German family owned discount supermarket chains. Apps are used to assign tasks to employees and they can update the status of the task so that managers can get updates on the employee from their system.

Technologies Used: Swift 5, Push Notification, StoryBoard and Programmatic Design.

# Snatch it. shop

Snatchit-shop transforms retail through "shoppable" content. We enable retailers' connection to our online marketplace to display their store and products for purchase. We increase awareness by creating new points of sale for your products using our unique influencer features. Influencers can create their own social shops using our app and earn ongoing commissions for their sales. We integrate with Shopify, Stripe, Zip pay

### **SKILLS**

Swift

Swift UI

Flutter

Objective C

MVVM

Firebase

### Swift Package Manager

JCTTool https://github.com/thobio/JC TTool

Make programmatic UI creation Simple.

### **LANGUAGES**

English

Malayalam

Hindi

and Google Merchants.

Technologies Used: Objective C, Swift 5, Stripe, Zip Pay, Shopify, Push Notification, StoryBoard and Programmatic Design.

# BDR(Banned Drinker Register) iOS Application (In-House App)

Banned Drinker Register App is an iOS app used to limit/restrict liquor supply for individuals. App Scans identification proof such as id cards, Driver's licenses, Passports, etc., of the Banned Drinker Register to restrict/limit liquor supply based on the user's status/quota.

Technologies used: Objective c, Acuant SDK, SOAP web services

### **ProptMe**

ProptMe. is a platform that lets you hire out household items or connect your business services with others. Users can search by area meaning you'll reach both a local and wider audience. It's completely FREE to list – meaning every dollar you make is yours

Technologies Used: Swift 5, Push Notification, StoryBoard and Programmatic Design.

# **BestRateJO Application** — *Detail*

BestRateJO is a Jordan-based company which is a hybrid platform focusing on financial services. You can now apply for a Loan and get approved through your phone without the need of leaving your house/office. You can also apply for Deposits, see the different rates given by the banks, and choose the one that most fits your needs.

Technologies used: Swift 5, MVVM, Rest API, Push Notification, Firebase

### **Brandesto**

Brandesto gives you the latest offers, trends and new arrivals from the shops you love. Track all the shops and things you love and get noticed instantly when there are offers and new products.

Technologies used: Swift, MVVM, Rest API, Push Notification, Firebase

### Think Ganesha

Think Ganesha, help Ganesha devotees and everyone who loves Ganesha to tell their stories through photos and their own words. It is quick and

easy. Just take photos and upload them at Think Ganesha, and review all entries.

Technologies used: SwiftUI, MVVM, Rest API, Push Notification, Firebase

### **Health Hub Plus**

Health hub plus Pharmacy is proud to be your source for all of your pharmaceutical needs and save your healthcare costs. Just upload your prescriptions. Get the medicines at your doorstep.

Technologies used: Swift, MVVM, Rest API, Push Notification, Firebase

# PubFinder Application (In House App)

Pub Finder is an application for searching the nearest pubs from our location using google Maps and GPS. Each listing will show what part of the business that pub belongs to, contact information for the pub and directions to it.

Technologies used: Swift 3, Rest API, Google Map, Push Notification

# **Money Tracker**

Money Tracker app is a simple and easy way to track your money. Enter your expenses and income, it will help instant control over your spending.

Technologies Used: Flutter, SQLite, GetX.